[narrator] Ten:
The ability to envelop your body
in a shroud of Nen aura,
making it tougher and slowing
the effects of aging.
Zetsu:
A technique which shuts off
your flow of Nen aura.
Effective for concealing your presence
and recovering from fatigue.
Ren:
A technique for creating
an especially strong Nen aura.
It is crucial for increasing your power.
Hatsu:
The release of your Nen aura
after using Ren to boost it.
These four elements
are known as the Four Exercises
and are critical to the mastery of Nen.
[theme song playing]
[clapping]
Splendid. Just splendid.
Including your last two matches,
you’ve made progress.
You’ve made the grade,
so set the place of your choosing.
I’ll take you on any time.
[determined grunt]
THE x TRUE x PASS
[narrator] Hisoka finally consents
to a fight with Gon,
who prepares by continuing
to train tirelessly in the use of Nen.
[Wing] Today we’re going
to begin our study of Hatsu.
Once you master Hatsu,
then you will have mastered
all of the basics of Nen.
At that point in your education
you’ll need to start developing
your own Nen style.
[Gon, Zushi and Killua] Osu!
[Wing] Hatsu is the technique
by which you control your aura.
In other words,
it’s the culmination of Nen abilities
of which there are six categories.
Enhancers strengthen and reinforce
natural abilities.
Emitters propel aura.
Transmuters change the quality of aura.
Conjurers materialize objects out of aura.
Manipulators control things with aura.
And Specialists are those
with a unique and distinct aura
that doesn’t fall
within the other five classes.
It’s incredibly important
that you find an ability that suits you.
What do you mean, ‘suits you’?
[Wing] Nen abilities are highly personal
with two areas of particular prominence.
The ability that you’re born with
and of course, the ability
you’ve refined later in life.
For example:
Gon here was born with muscles
that are more flexible and springy
than most.
His acute senses were honed
by a childhood spent mostly in nature.
So, you see, from the moment of birth
your Nen ability falls
within one of the six categories.
It’s possible for your Nen aura
to change types later on,
although that’s quite rare.
If you attempt to learn a new ability,
one that doesn’t fit your natural aura,
you will have a hard time.
This depicts the compatibility
of the six categories.
The closer a class is to your own,
the greater your chances of learning it.
If you are born with an aura
of the Enhancer category,
you will find Enhancer abilities
easiest to learn and master.
The adjacent Transmuter
and Emitter classes
will also be easy to pick up.
On the other hand,
the Specialist class,
which is furthest away,
would undoubtedly prove quite difficult.
I’ll demonstrate using skills
you’ve already seen.
Hisoka is able to change his aura
into a rubber-like substance.
So, he’s a Transmuter.
Gido uses his tops as a weapon
by making them spin faster,
which is an Enhancer power.
But trying to manipulate so many tops
as weapons
also requires the skill of a Manipulator.
Since that isn’t very compatible,
he wasn’t very effective.
As for Kastro,
his Tiger Bite Fist was incredibly strong.
Had he mastered it,
he would have been
among the strongest Nen users.
I believe that his aura
fell into the Enhancer class.
However, he made the choice
to focus his energy on the power
to create a double,
which is a Conjurer ability.
He also required
the ability of a Manipulator
to control the double.
As you can see,
both of those are relatively far
from the Enhancer category.
[Gon] So neither of them
was compatible with an Enhancer type?
Correct.
Learning an incompatible ability
requires a great deal
of work and natural talent.
As a result of the focus of his training,
he squandered most of his talent
in Nen ability.
What you’re saying is,
Kastro made the wrong choice.
He was such a great fighter.
What a shame.
What do you think?
Are you all
beginning to see the importance
of fully understanding your own aura
as well as its nature?
[Gon and Zushi] Osu!
[Killua] Okay, so…
if you don’t know your aura’s type,
like, what category it’s in,
is there a way to find out?
There is.
Water Divination,
a Shingen-ryu screening tool
for classifying aura.
It’s also used in training Hatsu.
Perform Ren with your hands
placed on either side of the glass.
Your ability will be revealed
by what happens.
[Gon] The water’s overflowing!
[Wing] If the volume of water changes,
then you’re an Enhancer.
This change demonstrates that my aura
falls within the Enhancer category.
Okay. Now it’s time for you to try.
So Gon’s an Enhancer, too?
-[Killua] Hm?
-[Zushi] The leaf moved!
That movement indicates
that you’re a Manipulator.
All right, then. That just leaves me.
[focusing grunt]
What gives? Nothing’s happening.
[Wing] Indeed…
The leaf isn’t moving either…
Does that mean…
I don’t have what it takes?
Oh, no.
Try tasting the water, Killua.
[Killua] Taste it?
Hey… I think it might’ve gotten sweeter.
Yeah, you’re right!
That’s true. It does taste sweet.
Wait… then this isn’t plain water?
Perfectly ordinary.
Only the taste of it has changed…
due to Killua’s aura.
What does that mean?
[Wing] It means you’re a Transmuter.
Wow!
You’re a Transmuter?
Okay. Now the three of you know exactly
what kind of aura you’re working with.
For the next four weeks,
I want you three to train
until you can make
a more pronounced change in the water.
[Gon, Zushi and Killua] Osu!
JUNE 11
JUNE 16
JUNE 20
[phone ringing]
[Gon] Hello? This is Gon.
[Hisoka] Hey… I’ve been waiting.
So? Have you made a decision?
[Gon] Yeah. July 10th.
That’s the day I’ve chosen!
[chuckles]
Okay.
I’ll be looking forward to it.
JUNE 22
[focusing grunt]
[tired exhale]
[solemn grunt]
JUNE 30
[focusing grunt]
JULY 5
Okay. Time to see what you’ve accomplished
with your training.
-Killua, you're up first.
-All right.
I'm done.
So sweet!
You’re right! It tastes like honey!
Excellent. And Zushi?
[Zushi] Osu!
[straining grunt]
[Gon] Whoa!
[exhausted exhale, defeated sigh]
That’s the best I can do!
That’s all right.
But it isn’t going to be enough to pass.
I’m afraid you’ll need to train
a bit more.
Osu.
Next… Gon.
Osu!
[glass crackles]
[both gasp]
Stop! Gon, stop!
The water increased so forcefully
it cracked the glass.
Honestly...
I’m impressed!
I was feeling pretty good about this.
All right, Gon, Killua.
Today, you are both graduating.
-Oh...
-Really?
-We did it, Killua!
-That’s awesome!!
Master… Do I graduate, too?
You still need to train
a little bit longer.
Osu…
Just keep at it.
Yeah. You’ll get it!
Osu...
-And Gon…
-Oh?
I’ve one more thing for you.
Something important I still need to say.
What is it, Mr. Wing?
The Other Hunter Exam…
You’ve passed it...
Gon Freecss.
Congratulations.
You made it!
[Gon] The Other Hunter Exam?
That’s correct.
You were able to pass with flying colors.
What do you mean, sir?
One cannot be a full-fledged Hunter
without learning how to use Nen.
Such skill and power are requirements
of a terribly dangerous profession.
One of your duties as a Hunter
will be attempting to apprehend
evil poachers and other such criminals.
You must be strong enough to fight crime
if you are to be a true deterrent.
But this power is highly destructive
when abused.
Revealing the existence of Nen
during the Exam
would be quite risky.
Therefore, only those
who have already passed the Main Exam
are tested.
Oh, I get it.
You would’ve tested us,
Gon at least,
no matter what happened, wouldn’t you?
[Wing] Yes.
I should also have mentioned
that the Grand Master of Shingen-ryu
happens to be Chairman Netero.
[Gon and Killua gasp]
[Wing]
The master has told me so much about you.
That goofy old man?
[Wing] Killua.
[Killua] What?
I want you to go back
and take the Hunter Exam again.
You’ll definitely pass next time.
-Oh...
-He’s right!
At this point,
you are more than qualified enough.
That I can guarantee.
Well… if I feel up to it.
[Gon] Hey, Mr. Wing?
Have you heard anything
about any of the other people who passed?
I have.
Hanzo and Kurapika
have learned Nen from other teachers.
Pokkle, on the other hand,
is struggling with Ren.
Leorio has begun studying
for the medical school exam.
Hisoka and Illumi were already
well-versed in the use of Nen,
so they were qualified, of course.
[Gon]
So Kurapika and Leorio are working hard!
[Killua] Yeah.
That’s not all, Gon.
I have one bit of advice.
When you fight Hisoka tomorrow,
don't push yourself too hard.
-All right?
-Right!
Zushi.
You will continue your training
for four more weeks.
Osu...
Have more confidence.
You’re really progressing
at an incredible pace.
You’re one in a hundred thousand.
Wait, I’m one in a hundred thousand?!
O-- Osu!
Those two, however…
are even rarer talents.
Perhaps one in ten million.
Osu!
Is that supposed
to make me feel better, Master?
[Zushi] But… One day…
I’m gonna catch up to both of them!
[Cocco] Hello, everyone!
In the arena today we have a match
between Gon and Hisoka!
The battle you’ve all been waiting for
is about to begin.
And as you can see, the stands are packed!
The fight hasn’t even started
and the tension in the air is palpable!
[spectator 1] How much longer?
[spectator 2] Come on, let’s go!
[flexes knuckles]
[determined grunt]
[cheering]
[Cocco] The first to arrive is Gon!
After four fights,
he has a three-one record.
He’s really on a roll!
[spectator 3] You can do it, Gon!
[spectator 4]
Hey, where’s your fishing rod?
You can’t catch Hisoka
with your bare hands!
[Cocco] And next, arriving in the arena
with a fiery display…
is Hisoka!
[cheering]
[Cocco] The memories
of his lethal battle with Kastro
are still fresh in everyone’s minds!
A nine-three record means a win today
earns him the right
to challenge a Floor Master!
He’s won every single match
he’s actually showed up for.
Will his undefeated streak continue?
[cheering]
[Hisoka] Oh...
Don’t look at me like that…
SCHWING
It’s really turning me on!
[Wing] What a sinister aura he has.
Gon… don’t overdo it.
[audience] Oh!
You win by points or knock out.
No time limit!
One round!
Begin!
[Cocco] This is the match
you’ve been waiting for, folks!
The die has been cast!
Who will make the first move?
It's Gon!
[Gon grunts]
[Gon grunting]
[short cry of pain]
[grunting]
[grunt of pain]
[excited roar]
[Gon grunting]
[roaring]
[grunt of pain]
[straining]
A clean hit! Hisoka: One point!
[audience roaring]
That... was an amazing exchange!
So amazing that I could barely
get a word in edgewise!
[chuckling]
What’s the matter?
I haven’t moved a single step
from where I started.
What? Really?
[grunts]
Dammit!
Well, just you wait!
[Gon] Okay.
I shouldn’t have to connect each hit.
I can mix in some feints
to get the same effect.
[Killua]
Hisoka looks like he’s having fun.
In terms of actual skill,
there’s a world of difference
in their combat experience.
But he still has a weakness.
Hisoka thinks he’s stronger,
so there’s no way he’ll ever back down.
That’ll give Gon a chance...
[Gon] Fine. I know just the trick!
[roaring]
[growling]
[Cocco] There it is! Gon’s Stone Flip!
[roaring]
[Hisoka] He shattered the tile
to create a hail of rubble.
Gon...
Where is he?
[no sound]
[narrator] Gon has finally landed
a critical hit on Hisoka.
But the match has only just begun...
and it won’t be long
before Gon experiences
Hisoka’s true power.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we're introducing Hisoka.
He reels in opponents
with Rubbery Nen called Bungee Gum.
And he uses Texture Surprise
to duplicate other objects.
[both] Schween!
[Gon] Next time:
“A Big Debt x And x A Small Kick”!
[Killua] Go, Gon, go!
[Gon] Gon Shot!